Maybe you'll laugh when I tell you...
or write it off as a fairy tale...
It couldn't possibly be true... I mean,
how could it?
[ music piano playing ]
[ humming a lullaby with piano ]
[ humming lullaby ]
This is a story about my mother
and it's true, every word of it.
The man that she fell in love with...
...was also a wolf.
Back then, mom was a student at
a national university in Tokyo.
She earned a scholarship to
cover some of her tuition.
And worked a part time job to
take care of all the rest.
[ professor speaking in front of class ]
[ professor continually speaking ]
One early summer day,
She noticed a young man,
she'd never seen before.
He wore a plain shirt with a
stretched-out collar,
And though he didn't have a textbook,
he took notes diligently.
She thought he looked out of place
in the lecture hall.
Um... excuse me!
You didn't fill out a slip. They'll mark
you down as absent, if you don't.
- I could grab one for you...
Don't bother. I'm not a student here.
Huh?
I shouldn't have come... See ya.
[ music piano playing ]
[ children chattering outside ]
Please, wait a minute!
That class you were sitting in on
is pretty tough even with a textbook.
So, I was thinking, that if you feel like
coming back for another lecture.
Maybe... maybe, we could share mine?
"Congratulations...
...we'll have it ready
for you on Friday. "
Thank you. Have a good evening.
Hello. Here to pick-up?
[ lullaby singing with piano ]
[ singing with piano continues ]
" Careful. "
" That's the last of it. "
[ dogs barking ]
[ professor speaking in front of class ]
[ singing with piano continues ]
" So... what do you do for fun,
and what are your favorite foods? "
" Have you ever,
you know...  fallen in love before? "
Ha.. ha.. Wait your turn.
Why were you named Hana?
Curious, huh?
Mm... Hmn
The day I was born, my dad noticed a
cosmos flower blooming in the back yard.
Nobody had planted it,
it just popped up.
That's why he named me Hana,
because it means flower.
He wanted me to smile all the time,
just like that comos did.
That way, whenever things were tough,
I could give life my best smile
and get through it.
Crazy as it may sound,
it always seemed to work.
When my dad died, I smiled from
ear to ear all through his funeral.
One of my relatives scolded me,
right there in front of everyone.
Said I was disrespecting his memory.
- Maybe it was disrespectful... I don't know.
No, I think you were perfect.
[ giggling ]
Good to know.
" Every apartment is like
its own little world inside it. "
Some families have money, some don't.
Five people live in that one.
In there... just two.
Some are full of kids...
Others, are all old folks.
[ train rumbling ]
- It'd be nice to have a home.
A place where I belong.
I'd kick off my shoes,
give my face a good washing
and sit back in a comfy chair.
It must be nice.
I could build a bookshelf.
And once I filled it with books,
what's to keep me from building another.
You just can't put a price
on freedom like that.
I could belong there too,
if you don't mind the company.
Hana.
Yes?
There's something I have to tell you.
I'm listening.
You see...
[ traffic passing noisely ]
Oh, never mind.
Okay.
[ holiday chimes ]
[ street traffic ]
[ people and city sounds ]
[ city quiet ]
[ silence ]
- Hana.
- I'm so sorry.
Really, I am.
[ Hana chuckling ]
- I've never told anyone about this.
- I was scared.
- I still am because it's you, but
you deserve to see me for who I am.
No, ...for what I am.
You're you.
- Close your eyes... Please Hana.
- Keep them shut.
I'm looking, okay ?
[ music piano playing ]
[ piano louder ]
Look at me.
Hana... Tell me what you see.
He told her that changing under
the full moon and attacking people...
were the stuff of dusty myths,
and bad movies.
My mother knew the world was full
of mysteries, but his heart wasn't one of them.
- Were you shocked?
- Are you leaving me?
- You're trembling.
- Are you scared?
No I'm not.
Because it's you.
Her beloved, my father... was a
descendant of the Honshuu wolf,
which went extinct
about a hundred years ago.
He was the only one left who carried both
wolf and human blood in his veins.
Dad's parents died
when he was just a boy,
but before they did, they taught him
the history of their kind.
And implored him never to reveal
his true nature to anyone.
After that, he lived with relatives
who never would have expected him
if they had known his secret.
When he was old enough
to get a driver's license,
he left for the city and never looked back.
He found a job and he kept to himself.
Dad had made peace with a life spent alone.
Until he met... her.
[ music starts ]
[ music continues]
[ music continually playing ]
[ music softly ]
" Natural Birth "
[ music continually playing ]
[ Hana starts crying ]
Mom gave birth to me in that
tiny apartment they called home.
No hospital, not even a midwife.
She didn't want to risk what would happen
if I arrived looking like a newborn pup,
So, dad and she did it alone.
Just the two of them,
bringing me into the world,
as the snow fell outside.
[ baby laughs ]
I'm so thankful that she's healthy.
Yeah, healthy and beautiful,
just like her mother.
I hope she has a gentle heart.
Yeah, and a good mind to go with it.
What will she grow up to be?
Whatever she wants, she can be anything.
For her, the sky's the limit.
I just hope she's happy,
that's my wish for her.
Then it's up to us, to make it come true.
Yeah.
[ baby gibbering ]
The following Spring,
my little brother was born.
It was raining that day.
Dad stepped out, but the day wore on
and he didn't return.
[ traffic noise ]
[ gasps ! ]
It was him.
I'll never know what dad
was thinking that day.
Maybe he was heeding the call of the wild.
Instinct, driving him out into the rain
to hunt down fresh meat for
his newborn and his mate.
Wait!
[ crying hysterically ]
No!
[ Hana weeping ]
[ crying ]
[ silence ]
[ silent ]
[ no audio ]
[ silence ]
[ Driver's License ]
" Take good care of our children,"
she thought she heard him say that
as he walked away.
I promise...  That's what I'll do.
I don't remember all the details,
but I know she had her hands full with us.
Food now.
- It's almost done, Yuki. Just be patient.
Food now!
- Look, I'm sorry, but I-
FOOD NOW!!!
- Yuki!
She said that I turned into a wolf
when ever I got cranky,
which happened a lot according to her.
- Okay forget patience, you can have
one biscuit, alright?
[Yuki giggling]
Not bad.
I had a ravenous appetite.
No matter how much I ate,
I was always asking for more.
My brother, Ame, was fraile
and hardly ate at all.
Between the two of us...
Mom had to put school on hold,
and quit her part time job.
Whoa!
Yuki!
Dad had left us a little money, but it
wasn't much in the greater skeem of things.
[ Yuki yelling ]
Ahh!
That was close...
Wolves or people...  We didn't know
how to be either yet,
and us switching back and forth
between the two...
didn't make figuring it out any easier...
For us or mom.
" Pediatric Care "
Ahh!
- You gotta be kidding me.
[ yawn ]
Mom had plenty of questions
but nobody to ask,
so she read every book she could find
and figured it out as she went.
She had to breastfeed Ame, every two hours.
If he was fussy and didn't want to nurse,
she'd soak a cotten cloth with milk
and let him gnaw on it for a bit.
[ Ame crying ]
[ Ame screaming ]
Some nights Ame would just cry and cry.
All mom could do was rub his back
until he tired himself out.
Even if it took all night.
[ rumbling ]
We didn't leave her any time to herself.
I'm okay.
When ever Ame and I gave her a moments peace...
she would nod off in a second.
Momma?
Yes baby?
[ Yuki giggling ]
Our getting sick, was a conundrum.
- Yuki?
Yuki.. what are you..?
Yuki..  !
Should she take me to a pediatrition or a vet,
it was anyone's guess.
My two year old just ate the inside of a silica packet?
Yes, a few times.
No... No blood.
I mean... I didn't see any.
Look, I don't even know what silica is!
I'm just afraid that it's toxic.
Huh? How's her appetite?
[ Yuki burps ]
Can I have a snack?
[ Yuki burps again ]
So you're saying...  She's gonna be okay?
So many times she
wished she'd asked Dad...
how he had made it through his
wolf childhood in one piece.
I wanna walk.
- Yuki, I don't ...
I wanna walk!
- You just got over being sick baby, remember?
I WANNA WALK!!!
- Alright, alright. I'll take you for a walk,
but tuck your ears in first.
- There that's a good girl.
[ Yuki barking ]
- Calm down, Yuki.
Your ears are out again!
Ready!
[ music and singing ]
Afternoon "Miss."  Cute kids.
Did you hear that?  He thinks you're cute.
[ dog barking ]
[ Yuki GROWLING back ]
Oh, I'm sorry!  I'm sorry!
Uh...
People were an issue at home too.
[ Ame crying ]
[ banging on door ]
- Come on lady!
Shut that kid up already!
[ crying stops ]
I'm sorry about the noise...
- How am I suppose to sleep with
him crying all the dam time, huh?
- He's a baby, they cry!
- Aw, that brat of yours needs a muzzle!
[ crying resumes ]
Shh... your okay Ame. Your okay.
[ kids giggling ]
[ howling ]
Shh!
[ howling stops ]
- We don't allow pets in this building, period!
How many times do I have to tell you?
I don't have any -
- I wasn't born yesterday, girl.
I've heard them, many a time.
- If you can't abide by the rules here,
you're going to have to
find another place to live.
It's that simple!
Child Welfare Agency?
Yes, ma'am. We're here about your son
and daughter, Ame and Yuki, right?
Here about them, why?
Ma'am, according to records your kids have never
been vaccinated or even once been to a doctor.
Care to explain this?
Well, they're fine.
Thank you for your concern.
We'd like to see them for ourselves,
in order to gauge their well-being!
I'm very sorry, but that's not...
Be reasonable!
It wouldn't take but a minute and we'll be
out of your hair, before you know it, alright?
You can't come barging in here!
If you don't cooperate with us, we'll have
no choice but to assume neglect!
Just leave us alone!
[ Ame and Yuki in distance playing ]
[ laughing and giggling ]
[ screaming and yelling ]
Come here.
- What is it, Mommy?
If you could only be one thing,
would you be people, or wolves?
[both reply]
Huh?
Maybe, we should move.
I want you to have that choice.
The town hall decided they'd like to
fill up some of the empty houses out here.
Sure the city folks snap 'em up, but
everyone of them throws in the towel.
None of them could handle living so far out.
It's a half hour drive to the nearest
elementary school.
And the middle school that's two and
a half hours away by bus and train.
And that's just one way!
Don't get me wrong it's a wonderful
environment for raising children, but-
where ever you're coming from
is way more convenient.
Wow...
It's so big...
They're renting it out for a song.
You'll be on the hook for repair costs.
And it needs a lot of work.
You can leave your shoes on.
This place has been abandoned for years.
Let's not kid ourselves, it's ugly as sin.
But believe it or not, the wiring is still good
and it gets water from the stream.
I'll even throw in all the stuff in the tool shed.
Does the land include that field?
Yeah, but I wouldn't go buying a
scarecrow just yet.
Unfortunately, it's not viable as farm land.
Animals come down from the mountain
and eat everything.
They sorta pushed folks out.
In most places, it's the other way around.
And are there any neighbors?
Well only if you use the term loosely,
there's no one around for miles.
So, on to the next?
There's a cute little house in the village I think you'll -
I'll take it.
Huh!?
This is the one I want.
It is?
- Woah! Where are we mommy?
- This is our new home.
[ footsteps running ]
Wow!
Look it, I'm a crooked little house!
We got ants for neighbors!
Whoa! What is that thing?!
Hey, Ame! Watch this!
Yahoo!
Ahh!
[ Ame screaming ]
So, what do think?
This place is great!
Can we go home yet?
" She didn't seem to care about
the lack of neighbors. "
" Who knows, maybe she's the eccentric type. "
Is she married?
Don't know...
Got a job?
Well of course she's got one, how is
she going to take care of her kids?
Oh, uh, Hey! Grandpa Nirasaki!
Try to go easy on this one, okay?
[ piano music ]
Ah.. choo!
Whoah!
[ hammering ]
Ah.. ahh!!
[ piano music ]
[ hammering ]
Eh..!
Ee..!
[ piano music contiues ]
Look at all this neat stuff I found!
Tada.. !
[ Ame screaming ]
Oh!
Hey birdie, I want to be your friend!
Here kitty kitty--
[ cat snarls ! ]
[ screaming ]
Suprise!
[ cat screams ]
[ giggling ]
[ Yuki laughing and barking ]
[ music continually playing ]
[ music softly ]
"Yuki - Age 5"
"Ame - Age 4"
[ Ame screaming ]
[ piano music continually playing ]
[ music softly ]
Ha ha!
[ laughing and giggling ]
[ piano music continually playing ]
- Have a good afternoon.
- Thank you.
- Oh, uh, hi!
- Hello dear.
-She's the one who just moved in, isn't she?
-I'm not sure.
[ music continually playing ]
Here we go.
[ music softly ]
Wee..!
We'll just have to be
more frugal from now on.
What's Frugal?
It means will have to grow our own vegetables
instead of buying them at the store.
[Yuki barks]
I'll help you grow 'em!
Wait right here, okay?
Mm.. hmn.
" Home Garden "
This should do it.
Sure.
These one's, too, please.
Ah! Yuki!
- Yeow!
Yuki, Ame, the two of you being wolf children
is our little secret okay?
Okay.
[ both reply ]
If you turn into wolves around people,
it'll suprise them too much.
No matter what, you need to be sure
never to do that.
Can you promise mommy that?
I promise!
[ both reply ]
And one more thing.
If you meet animals out in the woods,
make sure you're not bossy to them.
How come?
Because Daddy would want you to be nice.
So?  What do you say?
We'll be good!
[ both reply ]
" We'll never forgive you! The angry
villagers chased after the wolf with guns."
" I'm sorry! I won't do it again,
the boastful wolf cried as he ran away."
[ Yuki laughing giggling ]
Woohoo!
[ laughing cheering ]
Awww!
But why?
I don't know, honey.
- Uh? Excuse me!
Heh?
- May I take the fallen leaves
in the woods for fertilizer?
- Beg your pardon?
The fallen leaves!
- What are you asking permission for?
Just go ahead and take them!
Thank you very much!
" How long do you think she'll last? "
" Soon as she get to missing convenience
stores bad enough, she'll be gone. "
Aint that the truth.
[ both laughing ]
Grow this time...
[ whispering ]
- Mommy..?
Hm?
- Ame!
- What happened?
- What a baby!
The animals pick on him,
'cause he's such a fraidy-cat all the time!
They're just scratches.
You'll be fine.
- Ame's got to learn to be tough!
Yuki.
Am I going to be okay?
You'll be fine. I promise.
If a wild boar messed with me,
I'd beat it up!
- Have you run into one?
Uh huh, and a mountain goat and a monkey.
But I wasn't a big fraidy-cat.
They ran off when I barked at them,
so I chased them.
And then I...
- Yuki.
I peed all over them,
to show them who's boss!
Don't forget dear...
You promised that you'd be nice
to all the animals that you meet.
Yeah... But...
- For daddy.
Okay.
That's my girl.
Tell me I'll be fine again.
You'll be fine, just you wait, okay?
- How are wolf children supposed to
grow into adulthood?
- I feel like I'm making it up as I go...
- Yuki, wait for us!
- Carry me?
- Already?
- Come on slow pokes! Hurry up!
- " Wolf pups start figuring out how to hunt,
about four months after they're born."
At first, they practice on mice,
and other small animals alone.
Then, as they start getting older,
they start gravitating into wolf packs...
We're a pack!
Nuh, uh!
Fine, be that way.
- Don't run off too far, okay?
'Kay!
Mommy, I wanna go home...
Oh, Ame, I know.
Do you think this wild grass is good to eat?
Let's see...
[ music ]
Got ya!
[ hissing ]
I win!
Whoah ... uh..!
Look Ame, neat huh?
[ birds screeching ]
Better out than in, right baby?
Look what I found Mommy!
This silly bird was poking at me,
and I grabbed it!
Mommy?
Hmm?
How come the wolf
always has to be the bad guy?
You mean, like in the picture books?
Everybody hates them,
and they always get killed at the end...
because of that,
I don't want to be a wolf.
You're right, but you know,
mommy thinks wolves
are pretty nice people.
Even if everyone else is mean to them,
I'm going to stick up for the wolves
through thick and thin no matter what.
- Mommy? Mommy, come here!
What's the matter?
They're floppy again.
What?
What happened, a disease or something?
Their leaves...
- Mommy?
What's going to happen?
We're not going to starve are we?
We're going to be okay,
I just need to study harder.
Will you be my little helper again?
Uh huh...
Thanks sweety.
Go inside.
Okay.
Good evening!
I'm sorry we haven't made it down
the hill for a proper "hello" yet...
Growing your own produce is a lot
tougher than I thought it would be...
The books from the library
didn't really prepare me for all of this.
But, I think being up here is good for us.
All this nature, you know?
Hm.   All this nature huh?
Nature just killed your tomato vines,
what do you think of that?
Huh?
You can plant new ones 'til
you're blue in the face.
You ain't cut out for this life.
Well, guess I'll learn...
Oh.. Stop it. Smiling like that?
Makes you look like a damn fool...
[ engine revving ]
- That old man was scary.
Maybe, but he was right about me
not knowing what I'm doing.
- Even though you're a grown up?
I wish I'd asked your Daddy
how to do more things.
Whoo.. hoo! It's really coming down, huh?
Um...
Can I help you?
Here, these'll help.
Okay, what are they?
Some seed potatoes.
Seed potatos are the kind you're
supposed to plant, aren't they?
Ah, Ha ha ha...
Dad would burst a blood vessel if
he heard you ate 'em!
Don't you mind what he said about
you and your tomatoes.
He barks a lot, but he's harmless.
I didn't mean to get him all riled up.
[ laughing ]
Hey, ya kids!
- Oh, they're shy.
- Not a problem.
- Here.
Hey, Mr. Nirasaki, thanks a lot for
those potatoes you sent up.
Well, I should have just thrown them out.
Uh.. ?
Soil ain't ready for planting yet.
[ music softly ]
You're going to have to dig it up
a lot better than that.
- Oh, okay...
- Oops!
What about the fertilizer..?
- Did you use leaves from the forest?
Yeah.
- That's plenty!
- Umph... uh.
[ heavy breathing ]
When you're done, dig this part up.
Doesn't that seem like a bit much?
I don't think the kids and I can eat
that many potatoes.
What are you deaf?
Uh... Right...
[ soft music ]
Furrows are next.
Okay.
Stop crowding 'em all together.
- Right.
Too small... Make 'em bigger.
- Sure.
[ grunting ]
[ heavy breathing ]
[ music softens ]
[ music fades off]
A week from now, plant 'em
cut-side down in those furrows.
Don't you water 'em.
Just leave 'em be.
Well, I really appreciate
you taking the time..
to...
Mommy, are you okay?
[ crying ]
Oh...
My back is killing me.
Uh.  Hello!
Come here for a second.
- Huh?
We'll explain it all on the way.
- What?
Times a wasting, come on!
- Hey, Missy!
Uh, yes?
Chamomile with the cabbage,
if you plant them together, the bugs aren't
going to give you any trouble.
- Don't listen to him, cabbage and celery,
that's the way to go.
- Celery is no good for beginners,
chamomile is easier.
-What's she gonna do
with a bunch of chamomile?
Eat tea leaves all day long?
You should plant them nice
and shallow, like this.
- You forgot to water the hole!
The soil's not going to be moist enough.
- Yeah it is. You can water them all you like
after you've planted them in the ground.
- Not if you want 'em to grow!
Then you sprinkle a real thin
layer of fertilizer over it,
but don't over do it
or you'll get bugs.
- That shows what you know, more is better.
- Maybe that's why your crops never
grow worth a darn.
- Don't listen to this old goat if
you want to grow anything!
- You're one to talk!
- What did you say?!!
- Yeah, you heard me!
" What's wood vinegar? "
" It's made from charcoal smoke
and chicken manure."
" It's a home made way,
to keep pests out of your garden."
You really shouldn't have
gone to all this trouble.
I hope us dropping in unannounced
like this, isn't too much of a bother.
It's fine.
Working the land is hard
if you're not used to it.
Every day I feel like I'm
learning something new up here.
Most of the folks from the city
get discouraged...
and call it quits just as soon as they've unpacked.
Well, what kind of people did you get?
Old men, who thought they signed on for the simple life.
Talk the big talk, but they never did last long.
[ laughing ]
I know I preaching to the choir, but living
this far out in the boonies isn't the easiest way to go.
The irrigation is bad.
And we get a lot of snow.
Good thing we got each other, huh.
We just figured you wanted to be left alone.
Young moms like us are kind of an endangered species
around here, so we try to look out for each other.
Anything you want to know?
Uh...  Actually...
What?  So, you're just burning through your savings?
Yeah...  I need to start working, and soon.
Well, that's easier said than
done living way out here!
You better send your kids to preschool,
and get ready for one heck of a commute then.
Right?
[ both reply ]
Mommy, what's a preschool?
What?
And how come me and
Ame don't get to go to one?
-Well, that's because...
What ever it is, I want to go there.
No.
I wanna!
You can't!
I wanna go! I wanna go! I wanna go!
It's not fair!
I wanna go to preschool! I wanna go to preschool Mommy!
I wanna go..!
Yuki, you need to settle down now.
I know it's supposed to be a secret Mommy...
I'll be good I promise...
[ Yuki sniffling ]
Baby...
I won't turn into a wolf...
Huh?
Hmm... Huh?
[ Hana gasps ]
Y-Yuki...!
Goodness Hana, I didn't know you had a dog?
Oh.. Uh, yeah...
[ Yuki howling ]
That looks more like a wolf to me.
-I don't think that a dog honey..!
-I know it looks like a wolf, but...
You know darn well that's not wolf!
They're extinct in Japan.
That's a German shepherd mixed with another breed,
Isn't that right? Am I right, well aren't I?
Huh...  I wonder where it went.
Hi, Mrs. Nirasaki!  How are you?
Well hello, Yuki dear.  Aren't you friendly today.
Oh, you and your doggy's clothes match!
That is just adorable.
That's my Yuki! Adorable...
Something wrong, Hana?
[ chuckling nervously ]
[ music ]
[ all cheering ]
Ah!
- Hello?
Is anybody home?
I wonder where Grandpa Nirasaki could be...
Well, these are looking good... Thanks
It's the least I could do.
We where growing potatoes too,
but they all got dug up.
Dug up by what?
A wild boar.
Anyhow, these are for you.
Are you sure?  Oh, oof.
Damn that pesky boar...
Oh, much obliged for the potatoes Hana.
The boar snuck in, and tore my crops to ribbons.
It came all the way down
to Sakai's place. These are for you my dear,
but watch how you carry them,
because they're heavy.
You're the only one who's fields
didn't get touched by animals at all.
That's strange with how far out you live.
So, what's your trick? I'd love to know.
I'm just lucky I guess...
Oh, don't be coy deary.
What are they talking about?
Look out, I gotta pee!
My, she's a little spitfire.
I wonder if...
If what?
Oh, nothing, just talking to myself.
Wow, thank you so much.
- Least I can for all those potatoes.
We haven't had eggs in a while.
- Glad to be of help.
There's more where that came from.
Oh my, what a cute little fridge you've got!
Huh?
Cute?
Easy does it.
Please, this is way to much.
It was just gathering dust out in the shed.
At least this way, it's going to good use.
But, still...
If we come back home with this thing,
we're going to catch hell from the old man.
Grandpa Nirasaki?
It's always Hana this and Hana that with him.
He's got a crush on her.
Don't be silly, he's ninety.
Hey, all I know is that he told
everybody to look out for you Hana.
Idiot! That was a secret!
Oh... It all makes sense now.
I figured out why you had me plant so much...
We're all in this together.
Give it a rest.
Huh?
Walking around with that smile on your face...
[ Hana laughing ]
What's so funny?
[ Hana laughing louder ]
You just gonna stand there and laugh like a lunatic?
We moved here so the kids
grow up away from the prying eyes in the city...
Now we're in a place where
everyone looks out for us, and it's great.
I didn't think it would work at the beginning,
but I'm pretty sure I made the right decision.
[ all gasping ]
It snowed! Oh look it Mommy!
Ah!
[ Yuki laughing ]
Oh... Oof!
Ungh..
Ah!
[ all laughing ]
[ music starts ]
[ piano starts ]
[ music continues ]
[ music softens ]
[ piano continues loudly ]
[ all howling ]
[ music fades off ]
[ all laughing ]
[ bird flapping ]
[ Ame growls ]
[ bird squeaking ]
Mom! Mommy!
Mommy! Mommy!
Mom!
Come quick, Ame fell in!
Mom- Mommy!
Ame..
Ame I'm coming!
Ame!
Mom... my...
Mommy...
Ame... Oh, oh my god!
Ame!
Open your eyes! Ame!
Just open your eyes!
Ame, not my baby...
[ Hana crying ]
Open your eyes... Ame..
Mommy... You're squishing me...
Ame!!
You know what?
I saw a crested kingfisher Mommy,
and its feathers were so pretty...
I felt really good today... Like maybe I could catch it...
I wasn't scared,
'cause I felt like I could do anything.
So I creeped up on it, and it didn't even know
I was there because I was a wolf...
And then I caught it... Huh?
Why are you crying?
How come Yuki and me are all wet?
Years later when she spoke of that day,
she said it felt like her heart had stopped...
But for Ame, that day was an awakening.
His timid nature melted away...
The long winter finally ended,
making room for a spring that was ready to begin.
Elementry school was starting up again,
and I was eager to join the other kids.
In order to convince Mom that she should let me,
I did my best to be the perfect daughter.
I guess it worked,
because she finally agreed to let me go.
Under one condition...
- No matter what happens-
- I won't turn into a wolf.  I'm gonna be fine, okay!
Do you promise?
Yes. Cross my heart.
I even have a little chant
that might help you out.
Really?
When ever you feel like changing just say it.
How does it go?
♪ I'm gonna be a little girl, all the way home. ♪
Simple, huh?
I'm gonna be a...
- little girl, all the way home.
♪ I'm gonna be a little girl, all the way home. ♪
[ both laugh ]
[ Yuki giggling ]
♪ I'm gonna be a little girl, all the way home. ♪
Hurry up you two!
[ Yuki giggling ]
I had never been surrounded by
that many people in my entire life...
It was overwhelming.
I had wanted to go to school so badly...
That hadn't changed any,
but now that I was there,
part of me just wanted to run away.
But... I didn't feel that way for long.
[ up beat music ]
Have a good day Daddy!
See ya later Mommy!
Bye, Yuki! Be good, okay?
I will!
Shino, back here!
Good morning, Yuki!
Morning, I saved you a seat!
Thanks!
"1st Grade"
[ music continues ]
Who can raise there hand with the answer?
- I can!
- I can! Me! Me!
Yuki, don't run inside!
- Yuki, you can do it!
- Go! Go! Go!
-Yuki!
- Alright!
[ Yuki laughing ]
- Wow!
- Thank you very much.
- My pleaseure.
Hey... What ya lookin' at?
The wolf...
Huh?
"Niikawa Nature Sanctuary"
"Nature Conservationist Assistant Wanted"
"Hometown Nature"
[ music softens ]
Oh.
There's a school group here.
Want the tour?
Welcome to Niikawa Nature Sanctuary.
I'm Tendo.
One of the conservationists on staff.
Good morning Mr. Tendo!
There's more to a nature conservationist's
than most people would think.
Doing outreach with the kids, like today...
Conducting field surveys,
rehabbing the flora and  fauna, as needed,
and coordinating with the volunteers.
We wear a lot of different hats
at the sanctuary.
We have to be Jacks of all trades,
and specialists at the same time.
Look... We could use an assistant,
if that weren't the case,
we wouldn't have posted that job notice.
I'd be more than happy to bring you on.
Honestly, we keep this place going
on a shoe string budget. That said...
We can cover your training expenses, if
you decide to become a conservationist,
but that amount isn't very much at all...
[ music fades ]
A high schooler with a part-time job
would make more than you would here.
Knowing all of that...
...do you still want it?
I heard, that you're caring for a wolf
here at the santuary...
This is our timber wolf.
- He's very quiet.
Well, he's older now...
- Excuse me, Director?
Pardon me a moment.
Nice to meet you. I'd like to ask
something if I may.
My little boy here is a wolf child,
but then the wolf who was
his father passed away.
I'm a good mother,
but when it comes to raising wolf children,
I'm kind of in the dark here...
When you were learning to be a wolf,
what did they teach you?
Please tell us how you were raised in the woods.
I want him to know that half of himself.
Sorry about that.
He was a pet... Guess his owner was
wealthy enough to bend the rules.
but when ever he died,
nobody else would take the wolf in...
If I remember it right,
he was born in the Moscow Zoo.
So he isn't from the wild?
I don't think I've ever heard of a zoo
taking in ferral wolf before.
Zoo wolves are usually born in captivity.
This old fellow isn't our only tenant,
we also take in injured birds and raccoon dogs.
As soon as they're healed up,
we release them back into their natural habitat.
I'm going to go to that place a lot from now on.
You'll be okay with coming with me, won't you?
I'm gonna learn all of the things
about nature that I can,
and then we'll go home
and I'll teach it all to you.
I've never seen one before...
A wolf?
So did Daddy act like that one?
Not at all.
Good, I'm glad.
Why is that?
The one we saw today,
his eyes were kind of sad.
I wanted to meet a wolf like Daddy...
Your Daddy was special...
He was truly one of a kind...
As Mom settled into her new job,
I was coming to a stark realization...
Your's is so cute!
Your's is cute too, Keno!
I found a four-leaf clover, neat huh?
So did I!
Hey Yuki! Find anything cool yet?
Mm hmn.. Looky!
[ girls screaming ]
Other girls didn't think that snakes
were a particularly lucky find.
In fact... They were terrified of them.
Look it, my mom gave me her old jewelry.
- Cool!
- Wow!
I got this one from my parents
on my last birthday.
- Oh you're lucky!
- Wow...
So, what are you keeping in your treasure box?
Ready?
- Yeah, show us!
- Ooh, what's inside?
Tada!
[ girls screaming ]
Other girls also didn't collect mummified lizards
and the bones of small animals.
In that, I was very much alone...
I didn't know how girls were supposed to act.
All I knew for sure,
was that I was doing it all wrong...
That was when I made the decision.
From that day forth, I would be
more graceful and ladylike. Even if it killed me...
[ Yuki moping ]
[ Hana laughing ]
Ughn... Don't laugh at me!
I am in the middle of a crisis!
Why do you want to act like someone you're not, honey?
'Cause when I act like me,
they all run away screaming.
If it means that much to you...
Huh?
That evening,
Mother sewed a brand new dress for me.
I was so thrilled...
I watched her place every stitch.
Thanks to that dress,
I was able to fit in.
The other girls accepted me
as one of their own.
- Good morning!
Wow, your dress is cute!
It's wonderful!
It had taken a while,
but I had finally found my own pack.
Ame started school the year after,
but he was reluctant to go.
It goes, ♪ I'm gonna be a little boy, all the way home. ♪
Got it?
School's this way!
[ girls giggling ]
[ "1st Grade" ]
[ "2nd Grade" ]
[ "3rd Grade" ]
[ "4th Grade" ]
Good morning Tendo.
Well young Ame, got the day off?
Mmm. Mmm...
Playing hooky?
Yep.
You can come here anytime.
Careful he just might...
[ people chattering ]
Hey Hana, can you cover the counter?
- Coming!
[ birds chirping ]
All right class, listen up!
We're getting a new student today.
Make him feel at home.
Go ahead, introduce yourself.
I'm Sohei. It's nice to meet you.
Hi Sohei!
[ students chattering ]
So, at your house, do you have dogs?
Huh? How come?
'Cause you kinda... smell like you do.
No we don't.
For real? I was sure
you had a dog at home, or something like that.
What are you doing?
Hey, let me ask you... Do you smell that?
Smell what? What is it?
Hmn... Guess I just imagined it.
Which one do I take?
Yeah! This one!
Aw... Never mind!
Yuki, want to play?
Sohei's no good at Old Maid,
but he's really funny.
No, I...  gotta give this back.
What's up with her?
I don't know, she's usually super sweet...
So Yuki... What's up?
Come on... Talk to me.
Hey. Wait up!
Yuki!
Stop being dumb!
Just tell me the truth!
About what?
Did I like... make you mad or something?
No, you didn't.
Well then you hate me,
because I'm the new kid?
Is that it?
Look, it's nothing, okay?
Then why are you running away from me?
I'm not running away!
[ Yuki whispering ]
I'm gonna be a little girl, all the way home.
Hey!
[ violin starts ]
Wait up!
I'm gonna be a little girl, all the way home.
- Leave me alone!
- How come?
I mean it okay!
[ violin off key ]
What's wrong with you?
Let go of me!
Yuki! Yuki!
[ violin screaches ]
[ heavy panting ]
- Hana! You got a phone call!
Okay!
This is Hana.
Sorry to call you with this at work.
When I got here, my son's head was covered in blood.
No it wasn't.
Yuki...
She hasn't said a word since it all happened...
Did you really hurt this boy?
Did you apologize?
Do it now.
I'm not asking.
I'm sorry...
I'm very sorry about this.
What do ya say we put this whole thing behind us...
The school's insurance
will cover any medical bills you have, so-
Do you really think I'll let you
push this aside with a weak little apology?!
What does that help
if my son looses his hearing in that ear?
I'm holding you responsible for this.
If his ear doesn't heal,
I will take you to court for everything you've got!
Now, please Mrs. Fujii...
I'm sure it won't come to tha-
- Stop jumping to her defence!
My child is the one with the injury here!
A wolf.
What?
It was a wolf that did it.
It wasn't her, so lay off.
Sohei?
What on earth are you saying?
I'm sorry...
A wolf?
- Why would Yuki hurt him?
- I know he had a bandage on his head.
- For real?
What happened to Sohei,  Mr Tanabe?
He went home early.
Why'd he do that?
Because he got hurt.
Yeah but, how did Sohei get hurt?
I'd rather not-
Someone beat him up. That's what I heard.
That's uh...
Yuki!
- Oh man...
- See?
That's enough you guys!
Everyone just quiet down!
I tried to be good...
I kept saying it, but it didn't work.
Are they.. Are they going to kick me out of school?
Will we have to move away? Because of me?
I'm sorry...
[ Yuki crying ]
I'm so sorry Mom!
Mom, I tried so hard, but I-
I know you did baby...
[ Yuki sobbing ]
Huh? Wasn't that..?
[ piano music ]
It's homework... From Sohei.
[ piano softly ]
From you know who...
Oh...
- Hi Sohei!
- She went to hang out at Shino's!  I'm sorry.
Oh... okay.
- Hey, are you thirsty?
[ music softly ]
It's the least I can do...
You come so far to get here every day.
I don't want Yuki to stop coming to school,
that's all.
The day that you you got hurt, I remember
you said in the principal's office, that a wolf did it.
Is that... what happened?
Uh huh... I think...
I know it sounds crazy but, I saw it,
just for like a split second.
and when I woke up, my ear was all bloody.
The wolf was the one who hurt me, it wasn't Yuki.
It's no fair she got in trouble 'cause of it.
I know that, some of the other kids are sure
she did it, but they weren't even there.
- I see.
And may I ask you one more thing?
Do you hate wolves now?
Naw, I think they're pretty cool.
[ Hana laughs ]
I feel the same way.
Hey Yuki... Wanna see my ear?
Huh?
Uh...
Looks pretty cool huh?
Wanna touch it?
Does it hurt?
It itches.
Well... Come on!
I'm heading out.
Where are you going?
To visit Sensei.
Sensei?
He teaches me... About life.
I see... By yourself?
Mm. Hmn.
Be careful.
And don't stay out too late.
'Kay.
- Where's Yuki?
- Back in class again.
I knew she'd come around...
What about Ame?
He isn't... a big fan of school.
- Aint nothin' wrong with that.
Thomas Eddison never
made it through grade school,
didn't know that did ya?
Worked for him, and it worked for me.
Don't you tell that boy to drop out!
Oh, does anybody live
up on the mountain?
No, why?
Ame's got a friend he calls his Sensei.
Who ever it is,
I think they must be up there...
Doesn't ring a bell...
This time of year,
everyone is down here tending field.
- When it comes to the mountain...
Sensei knows everything.
He's been up there a long time.
- I'm surprised you get along with
somebody so much older.
You should bring him home to visit Ame...
Sounds like quite a guy... I'd love to meet him.
Sensei's not much for people.
Unlike the other animals,
he doesn't come down here often.
Then again, he'd probably be okay with you.
That's him.
This entire mountain is his domain.
Uh...
I wanted to thank you for teaching
my son the things that I can't.
[ music ]
[ music continually playing ]
[ growling ]
[ music soft ]
[ music continues ]
[ music loud ]
[ music slower ]
[ music softens ]
"Hometown Nature"
[ music continues softly ]
[ music fades quiet ]
You can take a bath now!
- You should have
Sensei teach you stuff too, Yuki.
Your hunting will get way better,
like mine did.
I can run through the trees way faster,
because of him.
Also, I can read the terrain better now.
You'd learn a whole lot.
What the clouds mean
and how to find water,
and also... how to get along
with the other animals you meet.
I don't want to know that stuff.
Why not?
Try going to school for once
if you're so eager to learn.
I like the mountain, it's fun.
I learn real stuff up there.
I like school, okay.
Why is that?
Look, just come to school already Ame.
No thanks.
Why not?
Because I'm a wolf.
You're a human.
No I'm not.
I've decided I'm better off
living as a human.
How come?
Tell me why.
Because that's what I am, got it?
I am a human!
According to who?
Stop asking me
all these stupid questions!
You know you're a wolf, Yuki.
Don't lie to yourself.
Just shut up! You don't know
what it's been like for me!
What's with you?
[ Slap! ]
You're going to school tomorrow,
you hear me?
No way!
You're going or else!
I said no!
...UGHH!
Wanna fight?
[ GROWLING ]
Hey!  What's going on here?
- Yuki! Ame!
[ clanging ]
[ GROWLING ]
What's gotten into you!?
Stop it!
Yuki! Ame! Please!
Don't fight!
[ GROWLING ]
[ SNARLING ! ]
[ thud ]
[ wood logs tumbling ]
[ door slams ]
Yuki...
Ame...?
What are you...?
Ame...
[ Yuki crying ]
Yuki and Ame are both starting
to choose their own paths in life.
I moved here to give them that freedom...
But now that they're spreading their wings, I just...
It's tough.. you know?
During my final summer
at grade school,
the countryside was pounded by a
number of record-breaking storms.
Ame started spending more time
up on the mountain then ever before.
He was worried about how all that
extra rain was effecting...
the plants and animals that
called the forest home.
Especially Sensei.
- Ame!
You had me worried sick, you know that?
Oh, you're soaking wet.  Hold on,
I'll draw you a hot bath.
It's Sensei... he can't move
because he hurt his leg.
I think.. he's going to die.
He's the guardian of the mountain
and everything on it.
Someone's got to take his place.
No way.
I don't want you going up there.
I mean it!
You're barely ten years old, Ame.
You're just a kid!
A ten year old wolf
is an adult, but that's different!
You're not a...!
[ gasps ]
[ heavy rain ]
Please.
Don't go onto the mountain again...
Please Ame... For me.
- Give it up man!
- You're not getting around me!
- Shoot it, Sohei! Pass it!
- Come on!
" - Hey did you hear? "
" - Hear what? "
" - My folks were talking last night,
when they thought I was asleep... "
" - Yeah?"
" - I heard them say that Sohei's mom, "
" - is getting married again! "
" - What? "
" - No way! "
[ girls chattering ]
" - Wait... So, Sohei is gonna have
a brand new dad then? "
" - That's kinda cool. "
" - Yeah, but get this. "
" - Sohei doesn't even know
his mom's getting married again. "
" - What? "
[ girls chattering ]
" - All this is super secret,
you can't tell him! "
- Yes!
All right!
[ boys cheering ]
Good morning, out there.
We're looking at a sunny day
for most of it,
but the rains will be
starting up this evening
and coming down hard
through the night.
It's so humid! Whew.
Yuki...
Hmm?
- Don't go to school today.
- What?
Just stay home with Mom, alright?
What for?
- You know the bus won't wait.
- I'm going.
Why don't you keep
her company, Ame?
- See you later, Mom!
- Have a good day!
In the northwest, sunny weather
followed by rain,
with sporadic lightning in some areas.
In the southwest, sun followed by rain,
but no lightning.
Ame?
And in the south east,
also sun with scattered showers.
Ame!
When weather's the common denominator folks...
Be sure to grab an umbrella,
when you leave the house.
Let's go inside.
What does the problem
want you to figure out?
In this case, it's how far a swallow
can fly in three hours?
Notice, how it says,
seventy km/h here?
That's short for,
seventy kilometers per hour.
This is the swallow's speed.
Once you know that much,
all you have to do is multiply
that seventy km/h by three hours.
Simple right?
The weather system along
the Sea of Japan is heading south,
Which is making atmospheric
conditions increasingly unstable.
In addition to the heavy rain,
we can now expect lightning
and sudden high winds
as part of the forecast.
Predicted rainfall will vary by location,
but conservative estimates
are calling for over...
seventy millimeters per hour
in the flat lands...
and upward of 100 millimeters
near the mountains.
Based on these estimates, the JWA
has issued a flash flood warning.
Use extreme caution
due to possible landslides,
and flash floods,
Take shelter in a building, and
if you can't, get to high ground .
[ wind rushing ]
[ radio chatter ]
Alright, you guys. Settle down!
It seems there is a heck of
a rainstorm, on the way.
So, we're ending the school day early.
Yay!
Wait! I wasn't done!
They're calling your parents
to come pick you up.
Head over to the gym, and you'll be
placed in groups based on where you live!
I hope you guys
got all that!
[ thunder crash loud ]
A blackout?
Sorry Mom.
" No, of course. I understand.
I'll head over right away. "
Ame, want to come
with me to pick up Yuki?
Honey?
Ame?
Where are you?
Ame!
Ame! Where are you?
Say something!
[ thunder ]
Takahiro?
Mommy!
Keiko! I'm here!
Coming, Daddy!
♪ Pease porridge hot ♪
♪ Pease porridge cold ♪
[ thunder loud ]
Why isn't Mommy here yet?
Try not to worry.
But, I'm scared.
Come on, getting stuck in school
till tomorrow could be fun.
I mean, we could play cards all night.
Oh, really?
I wanna play.
Yeah, that sounds like fun!
A sleep over!
I'll go get the cards
from the classroom.
Okay?
What card games do you play?
Well I know Old Maid, but that's it.
That's boring!
Hey, don't be a brat!
Shino! Are you in here?
Oh, it's about time!
What took you so long?
I know. But, this weather is
tough to drive in.
Hey, you want us to drop you off
on the way, Yuki?
Hmn? Good call... Come on,
grab your backpack.
- Uh... Actually...
What you waiting for?
Thanks for the offer, but I'm pretty sure
my mom's gonna be here soon.
- Really, it's no trouble.
- Yeah silly.
I don't want my mom to
come all this way for nothing.
That's a good point.
Well, we're off, then.
See ya.
Ame!
Can you here me? Ame!
Ame...
Please...
It's been a while... Where's Sohei?
Oh you're leaving?
Oh, did Yuki's mommy pick her up?
- The few of you left listen up!
Anybody who's still waiting,
come on over here.
We'll drive you home
in the school van, okay!
Ame!
Wait!
I'm coming!  Ame!
[ holding breath ]
[ whining ]
[ bear cubs whining ]
Ame...
Where are you...?
Why'd you come here?
Well, because...
...you disappeared.
They're gone.
Did they all get picked up?
It looks like even the teachers ditched us.
I just hope my mom's okay out there.
It's chilly.
Come on then.
- Yuki.
Oh, I'm coming!
What happens if no one
comes to get us?
I guess we'll live at school.
But, where do we sleep.
They got some beds
in the nurse's office.
And what about food?
We'll scrounge in the lunch room.
What they never comes back?
We just live here forever?
I'll get a job.
Delivering papers or something.
You're just a kid.
Who's going to hire you?
No problem. I'll just lie
about how old I am.
I can pass as a
middle school, right?
No way.
Are you sure?
I tired of feeling like a kid.
Me too.
Ame...
[ music soft ]
My baby... is out here... somewhere...
My baby is all alone...
I have to... keep him safe... no matter what...
I have... keep him safe...
Anybody in here?
He's gone.
My heart was beating so fast.
Hey, what were we hiding for?
Hey!
It's like an ocean.
Waiting to drown me.
Sohei, were you serious
about us  living here?
If nobody shows up, we gotta.
They will.  I'll betcha your mom's
on the way right now.
As if.
Why wouldn't she be?
You know why.
She got married again.
And she's having a baby with him.
Once it gets here, she's
not gonna need me.
But when your ear got hurt,
she was so worried about you...
Don't get me wrong.
It's not like I care.
I'll just run away from home.
I'll go be a wrestler or a boxer.
Live my life like a lone wolf.
So what do you think?
You don't have a muscle on you, Sohei.
You'll be out in a second.
I'll train.
Non-stop, cause I'm alone.
I wish I... I wish I could tell people the truth.
and be fearless about it,
and smile like it doesn't even terrify me.
Sohei...
That day when...
the wolf that appeared out of nowhere
and clawed up your ear...
It was me.
I wanted to tell you for so long now.
I couldn't not tell you anymore.
All this time. I knew.
Don't be afraid.
I never told anyone.
And I'm never gonna... Your safe.
No more crying.
I'm not crying, it's just rain.
Thanks Sohei.
[ footsteps aproaching ]
Ame... Where did you go?
Ame?
There you are!
I was looking for you.
Silly goose, lets go back
so we can go pick up Yuki...
Hana.
I missed you.
You've had to be mother and father both...
I'm sorry.
Mm.
I was watching you the whole time.
Yeah, I know you have.
You've done a good job raising our kids.
Don't lie. I messed up a bunch.
I mean it Hana.
Yuki and Ame have both grown up fine.
No, you're wrong. Because...
Oh... Ame's lost.
And I was... looking for him.
Ame?
Ame's fine. Trust me.
But he...
He's  an adult.
He knows himself.
An adult?
Ame knows where he's supposed to be.
[ music soft ]
Ame?
Oh, Ame!
This is what you want?
Aren't I...
Aren't I supposed to have taught you
something important in life by now?
What have I taught you?
And now...
Wait!
Ame!
Ame...!
Don't go...!
Ame...
[ music loud ]
[ Ame howling ]
He's right...
You're where you belong!
[ music louder ]
You'll be fine.
[ piano soft ]
It's been years now,
but Mom remembers everything
about that morning.
The leaves in the beach trees...
The glaring spider webs...
Even the sky itself...
All of them shown as if they
had been scrubbed clean.
In a single night...
The whole world had been reborn.
To Mom... it had been.
[ music soft ]
[ "Municipal Junior High School
Entrance Ceremony" ]
The next year, I moved away
from home to live in the dorms at the Junior High School.
Before I left, she reminisced about
the twelve years she spent raising us.
She said, that the time had
passed as though in a dream...  or fairy tale.
She smiled as she said it. Her gaze fixed at
the peak of the distant mountain top...
And in that moment... I knew I could go.
She was fine.
We all were.
Even now, she lives in that old
house in the country side. Alone...
But content.
[ music fades quiet ]
[ distant howling ]
[ Hana giggling ]
subtitles edited by
©  JSTAFF
Special thanks to
Numb 1 GI    and    Sniper Lord